welcome back to APUSH in under 3 minutes
no time for intros let's get into it so
in this time period African-Americans
both enslaved and free faced enormous
challenges but they also created
communities and strategies to protect
their dignity and Fight For Freedom so
what stayed the same and what changed in
the South enslaved people continued to
resist their oppression but their
efforts to end slavery were largely
limited to rebellions and most were
unsuccessful one of the most famous was
Natt Turner's rebellion in 1831 Turner
an enslaved preacher led a violent
Uprising in Virginia that resulted in
the deaths of over 50 people the
Rebellion terrified Southern whites and
led to harsher slave laws meanwhile in
the north abolitionist movements were
growing the free African-American
population increased especially in
cities like Philadelphia and Boston many
African-Americans founded their own
communities and institutions to preserve
their culture and fight for their rights
for example the African Meeting House in
Boston built in 1806 became a hub for
Education abolitionist meetings and
religious Services one key thing
African-Americans did was use the press
in 1827 Freedom's Journal became the
first first blackowned and operated
newspaper in the United States it gave
African-Americans a platform to speak
out against slavery and challenge racist
policies but you have to understand the
biggest thing that helped these
African-Americans was their own
spiritual commitment like for example
enslaved people in New Orleans gathered
at Congo Square on Sundays to play music
dance and preserve their cultural
Traditions these gatherings helped them
maintain a sense of identity and
Community even in the face of Oppression
so here's the line to take away from
this whole video while African-Americans
faced harsh conditions of discrimination
they found ways to resist and fight for
their freedom on the screen now are some
AP style questions for this topic pause
now I'll throw the answers up
now I will see you in the next one